Many years ago, mankind faced a divine fury.
In an event known as the Day of the Cataclysm,
our entire world was burned.
The fire raged with an intensity that threatened to reduce mankind to ash.
The places they lived, the languages they spoke,
the culture they had built.
None could escape its wrath.
Their base is one ramshackle shack.
Hello, Lieutenant Karim.
It's good to see you.
What brings you all here?
Tamaki, it looks like you're doing well here.
I'm glad.
We came here to compare notes on the Evangelist.
Hopefully we can all work together from this point forward.
If we end up going after the Whiteclad,
then I'm probably going to have to fight Cho again.
Stop spacing out and say something!
How did this happen?
You may not be the steed fated to carry me,
but you're still my comrade in arms.
We've been through a lot.
It's good to have you back, Silboro.
Could you maybe not put up freaky fake animal heads on our wall?
This Celestial Charger just returned to Earth.
Thanks to Vulcan's miraculous work.
Yeah, it's a donkey.
Are you really okay with this, Lieutenant?
Arthur, get back to work.
I'm guessing that hat came from Vulcan, too?
I found it by my desk this morning.
Those big horns.
Don't they get in the way a bit?
They don't interfere with my work.
No offense, Lieutenant,
but when it comes to fashion, you're oblivious.
You want me to help you pick out clothes sometime?
I wouldn't trust you to pick out anything
that didn't come from a fairy tale.
Well, you couldn't look worse than you do with horns.
Okay, that's enough idle chatter.
I feel like they do interfere with your work, sir.
Ugh!
Take what you got and leave now
You're wearing out your welcome
No one here wants to see you here, yeah
Think that you won from day one
But the devil will come
You know just why he wants you, don't you?
You're crooked, this iron
It doesn't feel so right
Missguided, defighted
And the final will raise it
You're starting a fight
You're trying to watch it burn
Try to save yourself like you always do
Every bridge we've built
You think it's just a burning death
Just burn it down
When everything is gone
You wish you only heard us out
Heard us out
Screaming, my time
My time
Thank you, miss
That's kind of you
I made it with my guts, sir
What gives, Obi?
Why do you have Iris doing the work of a common housemaid right now?
No, it's okay, sister
I offered to do this
But hey
What are you sitting like that for?
I'm sitting up here because I refuse to be placed at the same level as this gravel
Would you feel better if I sat on the floor then?
I would
Go ahead and get down there
What's the holdup?
You offered, so hop to it
Damn it
I wasn't actually offering to
It was just a little joke quip
All right
Let's skip the formalities and get right to the meat of it
We'll share what information we've scrounged up
See if that gives us any clues
Then decide how to deal with the white clad moving forward
My company didn't think the white clad existed until now
So we're still playing catch-up
Benny asked me to come on his behalf
But I won't have much to contribute
White clad operatives have made countless infernals
They're especially likely to be the orchestrators of any mass combustion events
Rekka Hoshimiya wasn't turning those kids to cause chaos
He wanted to find a compatible host for the so-called pilot light
So those bugs do more than create infernals
They're also used to find people with a special ability
Dr. Giovanni's a white clad
And he was looking for the key to Amaterasu
I guess these guys have plans for our perpetual power plant
The media's been told that the man who attacked Vulcan
Was actually an imposter wearing a mask that looked like Giovanni's
But the man Company 3 sent to their press conference was the real fake
Hijima wanted to prevent a scandal
So they made a new captain
Vulcan's seen Giovanni's face and he said that wasn't him
So we're safe to assume the real Giovanni took off
I hear that quite a few soldiers have suddenly disappeared from the third
It seems likely that all of them were white clad spies as well
They've probably all returned to the Evangelist by now
I have no idea if Hijima itself has been compromised
But as long as the third has its backing, they're out of the government's reach
The longer we wait, the bolder and more radical the white clad are gonna get
Till we know how to root out their spies
We should look for their base and hit them directly
I agree and I've already got my man Leek looking into the base's location
So tell me, how's the special fire force been treating you?
The gig's been downright convenient for me
Got me permission to come to this crime scene
Is that really all you need to find the white clad base?
Nah, even I need more than this
Do you believe Leek is trustworthy?
So far at least, he's doing good work for us
Once we've pinpointed the location of the Evangelist
The Eighth will move in and take him out
Is the Eighth up to that task?
About half of your company's fighters are rookies, correct?
It'd be a shame if some meathead led them to their doom
You might find the Evangelist's base
But the Eighth isn't strong enough to attack it yet
Are the white clad that strong?
You have no idea
Having seen their commander's power first hand
I believe it comes from a direct link to the Evangelist
An Adola link, huh?
So what does the Eighth need to do to get strong enough?
Our company's rookies are fine soldiers
They've got solid instincts and powerful abilities
But they still have room to grow
How can we help them do that quickly?
When I saw them sparring at the first
They struck me as green and wet behind the ears
They've got first-class, top-notch powers
But they need more combat training
Combat training, eh?
I just happen to know the best fighter in the entire force
Why don't you send them back with me?
What matters most is that our Devil gets stronger
Can you think of a way to upgrade his flames?
I might have an idea
But whether or not he catches up to you and show
That depends on him
Gondro, what's going on?
Huh?
And why should I agree to babysit their rookies?
Say what?
I owe them?
Oh yeah
Guess I do
Hey, Captain Shinmon
It's me, Shinra Kusikabe
Um, is everything okay, Captain?
In a real fight, you'd be dead
Okay, step right up, people!
Lesson one
You never know when a foe might strike
So stay sharp
Dumbass
What part of stay sharp did you miss?
Who's dumb now?
Iron Medillo
The magnetic extinguishing ball
So how does it work?
I'll let you see for yourself
And there it goes
It hits the fire with a quick magnetic blast
And the flames sputter out a second later
Way to go, Vulcan
An unpowered person like me
Could make good use of that
Shinra and Arthur are getting special training
In Asakusa, right?
I don't want to get shown up
So I figured I'd make us some new tools
You aren't relaxing, are you?
There are no rules in a real fight
Which means you can't predict when something might happen
Getting tired?
Y-yes, sir
That's because you know your life isn't on the line
You need to act like it is and channel all that tension you're feeling
Let that stress heighten your awareness
Feel life around you
Not just your allies
But your enemies, too
Focus on the lives at stake in a fight
And you can turn stress into a tool
So we should value life
Channel it
When you're feeling alive in that way
Self-defense becomes reflexive
All right
Let's get some practice in
Come at me like I'm out for your lives
Ah, so it begins
Kill him, Waka!
That's enough
Already?
Your technique isn't bad, but you're not about to hit me
All of your attacks are completely predictable
You need to shake things up somehow
And how do I do that?
Well, I think you need what I call
A finishing move
Like an ultimate
That's what happens when you let your guard down
What you need is a finishing move that capitalizes on your speed advantage
Well said, Captain Sheenmon
You're not just crazy strong
You're perceptive
Huh?
Hi
It's nice to meet you
I'm the head of the eight's one-man science team
And I'm here to crash your party
My name is Victor Leet
I've thought of a way to help Shinra give himself a power boost
I'm gonna need help to demonstrate
Hey, Captain!
Could you help me out for a second?
Depends on what you want
I want to show Shinra how jet propulsion works
If he can emulate it, he should get a lot more burst firepower out of those V to his
If he compresses his fire as he emits it
The thrust he gets will straight up skyrocket
So basically, you want me to show him how to tighten a flame?
Yes, I do
Will this be enough firepower?
Yes, it will
That was awesome!
See, when you fly normally, your flames get pushed out in all sorts of useless directions
Rain them in a bit, and you can take advantage of all that raw power you've got
If you can do like the captain showed you
And condense your flame so it only shoots one way
It should increase your speed by a good margin
And if I can do that, then I'll have my ultimate attack
I want you to focus on making that finishing move of yours work, Shinra
Sir
Arthur, your power is already a finishing move
Let's just keep sparring, work on the basics
Come try to kill me
Alrighty then, let's watch this cookie crumble
I have to say, you've got a different air than the rest of the 8th
I heard that you were sent there by Hajima Industries
A different air, huh?
You trying to say I'm too smart for them?
Too strange
Try anything funny with them and I'll dump you in the sea
Why does everyone think I'm a traitor?
What did I do?
I fly with my toes
Fine-tune my positioning with minor movements
If I don't pay attention to that, I lose my balance
But when I'm trying to squeeze my flame tighter, I really want to scrunch up my feet
Since I haven't even made it work once yet, there's no point thinking
Just need to plug on for now
I think he might be on to something
You can deal with most problems by saying one of two things
Time to give up or whatever, just do it
For a brilliant scientist, that's a real simple way to think
Eh, sometimes thinking's pointless
If you're at the start line of a race against rivals you don't know on a track you've never seen
You gotta start running
The toughest problems are solved by throwing effort at the wall and seeing if it breaks
That's certainly a surprise
I think we might have something in common after all
Captain Shinmon has perfect control of his flames
How does he do it?
There's got to be some kind of secret
I've told you before and I'll tell you now
We do not play with fire here
Now what can I do to help you remember?
It isn't what it looks like, sir
Spudder and Flare have an important mission this time
Has your obsession with fairy tales finally driven you mad?
She's telling you the truth, Lieutenant
I made Maki some new equipment and it needs Spudder and Flare to operate
What?
I gave the twin hover units a name
It's Tekkyo
They use Spudder and Flare as power sources
Which means Maki can use your second-gen powers to move them
What exactly do they do?
They're pretty much flying hammers
I know a lot of pyrokinetic enemies are flame resistant, so I figured these might help
So what do you think?
I think you three just passed your flight test
Then the Spud Flare witch is ready for action
Yeah, that isn't what we're calling him
The name's Tekkyo
Many years ago, mankind faced a divine fury
In an event known as the Day of the Cataclysm
Our world was bathed in fire
The fire raged with an intensity that threatened to reduce mankind to ash
The places they lived
The languages they spoke
The culture they had built
None could escape it
Come on
Tighten up
I got plenty of fire
I just need to pinch it
Your flames haven't changed at all
Like all you can do is switch between gross faces
What?
Was the face I made that weird?
If by weird you mean disgusting, sure
The fugliest pucker face I've seen
Guess this gesture won't work either then
I could try the one that Captain Obi likes to do
Rock and roll!
The hell was that?
Did Shinra just rip a huge fart through his feet?
Huh?
Now it's you who's not on guard!
Doesn't count as a sneak attack if you announce it
Good try though
You've got your head in the right place now
Think he's dead
Shinra, show me what you're doing
I saw you make gestures with your hands
When you powered up your flames
So I thought I'd try it out for myself
I got the last one I tried from Captain Obi
And I don't know
I feel like this one might have done something
No dice
Take off your gloves so I can see what you're trying to do
Yes sir
You saw me using hand forms
Which are also known as kata
They were commonly used by the martial artists of old Japan
There are many
I usually use this one to control my fire
But every single one of these kata is meant to have a different effect
There's even one that channels power to the user's feet
It's called tiger crusher
Watch closely
Put your index finger on the base of your thumb
And bend your thumb pushing it towards the base of your pinky
By using these kata
You can channel your energy or ki into certain parts of your body
This also affects your flames
Amazing
I had no idea
Yeah
Good luck
Thank you for the help sir
We've got more training to do
Up and at them
So I bend both my index finger and thumb inward
Focus on channeling energy into my feet
I think that was it
My fire compressed
I was about to blast off like a rocket
The tiger crush is amazing
So this is how my power works
By channeling the flow of my body's energy
I can master my flames
I feel the heat in my feet
The shape of my hand
Pushes all my strength down
Sho needs my help
I need to reach him as fast as possible
Faster
Okay
I think I see what Joker sees in you now
Pretty impressive
Hey
I'll give you credit for being quiet that time
Sheena
Use that speed boost to come after me now
Benny was really dreading this
I'm glad to see he's having fun now
Is he?
It's hard to tell from looking at his face
Two fighters who are worth training have come his way
I bet you Benny's ecstatic right now
A true knight never surrenders
It looks like your friend's pretty worn out
I think we better call it a day
It looked like you got knocked around a lot
You good?
Of course
Knights are resilient
So tell me
Do you have a name for that new finishing move?
Oh yeah
My ultimate attack
Stay sharp
So what's this move of yours called?
The kicker mandate
Overruled
What do you think?
They any good?
Yeah, but there's still just a couple of kids
Too shaky for their own good
We'll make a proto-nationalist swordsman of you yet, kid
That single-edge blade isn't like yours
It works differently
It's own technique
But it never hurts to learn, right?
Okay, you did good
Would have hit me if I hadn't known
Use it wisely
Sir!
I heard about your brother, Sho
How he's the only family you have
Keep him safe, okay?
Thank you, sir
Will do
I'm coming, Sho
You're soif
指を立ててきた奴が その爪で誰かを守る
武器は傷と立てる代わる 人生なんてそんなもんなんじゃないの
ずっと消えそうで 消えないような 誰にも知れない
I'll see you next time.